<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- AppStream metainfo, required by Flathub. Validate it with the appstream mode of
     flatpak-builder-lint (see packaging/README.md; note that an XML comment may not
     contain a double hyphen, so the command line can't be written out here).

     Screenshot URLs must stay reachable: Flathub re-fetches them on every rebuild and
     a 404 fails the build. They are served from docs/public/screenshots/ via the
     VitePress site, so regenerating screenshots keeps these URLs valid. -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.vietanhdev.bulwark</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
  <name>Bulwark</name>
  <summary>Security and antivirus scanner for Linux</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Bulwark scans a Linux host for security misconfigurations and intrusion
      indicators using a native Rust rule engine over declarative YAML rules, and
      explains findings in plain language with a suggested fix.
    </p>
    <p>Bulwark checks:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>System configuration — SSH, sudo, kernel parameters, cron, file permissions</li>
      <li>Persistence and intrusion indicators, including promiscuous network interfaces</li>
      <li>File integrity against a recorded baseline</li>
      <li>AI coding assistants, for API keys leaked into transcripts and for agent
          configuration a prompt injection could turn into code execution</li>
      <li>Viruses and malware, using ClamAV when it is installed</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Findings are sorted by how much they matter, and many come with a reversible
      fix that previews its changes before applying them — tightened file permissions,
      hardened SSH settings, redacted secrets — each shown as a preview first, so you
      decide before anything changes.
    </p>
    <p>
      Bulwark keeps watching after the first scan. It re-runs its checks on a timer,
      notices when a watched file changes, and tells you only when something genuinely
      new appears rather than repeating what you have already seen. A history view
      shows how the machine's posture has moved over time.
    </p>
    <p>
      Everything runs locally. The scanning engine makes no network calls and sends no
      telemetry; findings stay in a database on your own machine.
    </p>
    <p>
      Notes for this Flatpak build: Bulwark reads the host read-only to audit it, and
      never writes to host configuration on its own. Virus scanning uses the ClamAV
      already installed on your system, so signatures stay whatever your distribution
      keeps current. Checks that need administrator access run on the host and require
      the Bulwark command-line tool to be installed there as well; without it, every
      check that does not need root still works.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.vietanhdev.bulwark.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://bulwark.nrl.ai/screenshots/overview.png</image>
      <caption>An overall safety score, with findings sorted by how much they matter</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://bulwark.nrl.ai/screenshots/agent-security.png</image>
      <caption>Scanning AI coding assistants for leaked secrets and risky configuration</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://bulwark.nrl.ai/screenshots/compliance.png</image>
      <caption>Hardening checks grouped by category, with a compliance score</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://bulwark.nrl.ai/screenshots/antivirus.png</image>
      <caption>ClamAV virus scanning with live per-file progress</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://bulwark.nrl.ai/screenshots/rules.png</image>
      <caption>Every check Bulwark runs, explained in plain language</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://bulwark.nrl.ai/screenshots/settings.png</image>
      <caption>Appearance, and how often Bulwark re-checks the machine on its own</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://bulwark.nrl.ai</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/vietanhdev/bulwark</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>

  <developer id="com.vietanhdev">
    <name>Viet-Anh Nguyen</name>
  </developer>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#fbeee7</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#2a1a1c</color>
  </branding>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.8.7" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Virus scanning and administrator checks now work in the sandboxed builds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Virus scanning uses the ClamAV already installed on your system, with its current signatures</li>
          <li>Checks that need administrator access can now run</li>
          <li>The interface no longer stutters — a rendering workaround that was slowing it down has been removed</li>
          <li>Clearer explanations when a feature genuinely isn't available, instead of advice that cannot help</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.6" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes the application window being empty in the Flatpak and Snap builds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The interface now loads correctly instead of showing a sandbox error on an empty window</li>
          <li>Restores the system tray icon, so monitoring keeps running when the window is closed</li>
          <li>Opening or showing a flagged file works again</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.5" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes opening files from a finding, and restores the system tray icon.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Opening or showing a flagged file works again instead of reporting a sandbox error</li>
          <li>The system tray icon is back, so monitoring keeps running when the window is closed</li>
          <li>Clearer message when a scan needs administrator access, which the sandbox cannot request</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.4" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes the application failing to start in this Flatpak build.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The application no longer closes immediately on launch when the system tray library is unavailable; it now starts normally and runs without a tray icon</li>
          <li>Security checks are found correctly again, so continuous monitoring works instead of being silently switched off</li>
          <li>When no tray icon is available, closing the window now quits the application rather than hiding it out of reach</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.3" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes scan history not being saved in this Flatpak build.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Findings are now stored in the application's own data directory, so scans are recorded correctly</li>
          <li>Removes a sandbox permission that is no longer needed</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.2" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixes the Ubuntu PPA build, so the command-line tool can be installed with apt</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.1" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging fixes for this Flatpak build.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Adds screenshots and release notes to the store listing</li>
          <li>Ships a higher-resolution application icon</li>
          <li>Drops a sandbox permission the application does not use</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Distribution and packaging release.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Published to the Ubuntu PPA, with classic Snap and Flatpak packaging</li>
          <li>Install-verification in CI asserts each package actually ships its rule pack</li>
          <li>Browser-driven interface tests for the desktop app</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic fixes and remote scanning.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Reversible fixes for file permissions and SSH server configuration,
              previewed before they are applied</li>
          <li>Scan a remote machine over SSH, with an isolated per-host history</li>
          <li>Secret-detection accuracy fixes, removing false positives from
              placeholders and test fixtures</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
