<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- AppStream metainfo, required by Flathub. Validate it with the appstream mode of
     flatpak-builder-lint (see packaging/README.md; note that an XML comment may not
     contain a double hyphen, so the command line can't be written out here).

     Screenshot URLs must stay reachable: Flathub re-fetches them on every rebuild and
     a 404 fails the build. Flathub also requires them pinned to a tag or commit rather
     than a branch or a live site, so they point at raw.githubusercontent.com at a
     release tag. Bump that tag when the screenshots are regenerated. -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.vietanhdev.bulwark</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
  <name>Bulwark</name>
  <!-- Flathub caps the summary at 35 characters (ideal 10-25): sentence case, no full
       stop, no leading article, no app name, no "app"/"tool", no platform name, and
       understandable without technical knowledge. -->
  <summary>Find security risks on your system</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Bulwark scans a Linux host for security misconfigurations and intrusion
      indicators using a native Rust rule engine over declarative YAML rules, and
      explains findings in plain language with a suggested fix.
    </p>
    <p>Bulwark checks:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>System configuration — SSH, sudo, kernel parameters, cron, file permissions</li>
      <li>Persistence and intrusion indicators, including promiscuous network interfaces</li>
      <li>File integrity against a recorded baseline</li>
      <li>AI coding assistants, for API keys leaked into transcripts and for agent
          configuration a prompt injection could turn into code execution</li>
      <li>Viruses and malware, using ClamAV when it is installed</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Findings are sorted by how much they matter, and many come with a reversible
      fix that previews its changes before applying them — tightened file permissions,
      hardened SSH settings, redacted secrets — each shown as a preview first, so you
      decide before anything changes.
    </p>
    <p>
      Bulwark keeps watching after the first scan. It re-runs its checks on a timer,
      notices when a watched file changes, and tells you only when something genuinely
      new appears rather than repeating what you have already seen. A history view
      shows how the machine's posture has moved over time.
    </p>
    <p>
      Everything runs locally. The scanning engine makes no network calls and sends no
      telemetry; findings stay in a database on your own machine.
    </p>
    <p>
      Notes for this Flatpak build: Bulwark reads the host read-only to audit it, and
      never writes to host configuration on its own. Virus scanning uses the ClamAV
      already installed on your system, so signatures stay whatever your distribution
      keeps current. Checks that need administrator access run on the host and require
      the Bulwark command-line tool to be installed there as well; without it, every
      check that does not need root still works.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.vietanhdev.bulwark.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/v0.8.8/docs/public/screenshots/overview.png</image>
      <caption>A safety score with findings ranked by severity</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/v0.8.8/docs/public/screenshots/agent-security.png</image>
      <caption>Checking AI coding assistants for leaked secrets</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/v0.8.8/docs/public/screenshots/compliance.png</image>
      <caption>Hardening checks grouped by category</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/v0.8.8/docs/public/screenshots/antivirus.png</image>
      <caption>Virus scanning with live progress</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/v0.8.8/docs/public/screenshots/rules.png</image>
      <caption>Every check explained in plain language</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/v0.8.8/docs/public/screenshots/settings.png</image>
      <caption>Appearance and automatic re-check frequency</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://bulwark.nrl.ai</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/vietanhdev/bulwark</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/vietanhdev/bulwark/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>

  <developer id="com.vietanhdev">
    <name>Viet-Anh Nguyen</name>
  </developer>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <!-- Flathub rejects brand colours that are white, black or near-grey: they must be
       colourful and must differ between the two schemes. The previous pair (#fbeee7 /
       #2a1a1c) was near-white and near-black. Both below are tints of the app's own
       accent, #E95420 (styles.css). -->
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#ffd3bd</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#7a2d10</color>
  </branding>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.10.0" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>One-click fixes for common problems, and a view of how your machine measures up against PCI DSS, HIPAA and ISO 27001.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Findings that Bulwark knows how to repair now carry a Fix button, and a Fix All button repairs everything safe to change at once</li>
          <li>Every fix shows exactly what it would change and waits for you to confirm — nothing is altered on the first click, and the original is backed up</li>
          <li>New repairs for network kernel settings, login password ageing policy, and the legal warning banner</li>
          <li>Leaked secrets found in AI assistant files can now be redacted one at a time, instead of only all at once</li>
          <li>New compliance view maps each check to the PCI DSS, HIPAA and ISO 27001 controls it answers to, and scores only what was actually assessed — a check that could not run is reported as unassessed rather than counted as a pass</li>
          <li>Fixed the application icon not appearing correctly on GNOME, and sharpened it on high-resolution displays</li>
          <li>Calmer highlighting when moving the pointer down a long list of checks</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Bulwark now runs on 64-bit ARM machines as well as x86_64.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Desktop app and command-line scanner are both available for arm64, so Bulwark runs on a Raspberry Pi, an Ampere or Graviton server, or a Linux VM on Apple silicon</li>
          <li>Every arm64 package is built, installed and launched on real arm64 hardware before release — not emulated</li>
          <li>The desktop app is now checked for a window that genuinely renders its interface, rather than only for starting without an error</li>
          <li>Fixed a packaging fault that could bundle an unusable copy of the command-line scanner inside the desktop app, breaking privileged scans</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.9" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Store listing corrections. No changes to the application itself.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Shorter summary, and screenshot captions trimmed to one line each</li>
          <li>Brand colours now use the application's own accent instead of near-white and near-black</li>
          <li>Screenshots are served from a fixed release tag, so a listing can never point at a moved image</li>
          <li>The licence text is now installed with the application</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.8" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes an error when checking for antivirus support.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>When ClamAV isn't installed, Bulwark now says so plainly instead of reporting a check failure</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.7" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Virus scanning and administrator checks now work in the sandboxed builds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Virus scanning uses the ClamAV already installed on your system, with its current signatures</li>
          <li>Checks that need administrator access can now run</li>
          <li>The interface no longer stutters — a rendering workaround that was slowing it down has been removed</li>
          <li>Clearer explanations when a feature genuinely isn't available, instead of advice that cannot help</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.6" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes the application window being empty in the Flatpak and Snap builds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The interface now loads correctly instead of showing a sandbox error on an empty window</li>
          <li>Restores the system tray icon, so monitoring keeps running when the window is closed</li>
          <li>Opening or showing a flagged file works again</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.5" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes opening files from a finding, and restores the system tray icon.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Opening or showing a flagged file works again instead of reporting a sandbox error</li>
          <li>The system tray icon is back, so monitoring keeps running when the window is closed</li>
          <li>Clearer message when a scan needs administrator access, which the sandbox cannot request</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.4" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes the application failing to start in this Flatpak build.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The application no longer closes immediately on launch when the system tray library is unavailable; it now starts normally and runs without a tray icon</li>
          <li>Security checks are found correctly again, so continuous monitoring works instead of being silently switched off</li>
          <li>When no tray icon is available, closing the window now quits the application rather than hiding it out of reach</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.3" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes scan history not being saved in this Flatpak build.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Findings are now stored in the application's own data directory, so scans are recorded correctly</li>
          <li>Removes a sandbox permission that is no longer needed</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.2" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixes the Ubuntu PPA build, so the command-line tool can be installed with apt</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.1" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging fixes for this Flatpak build.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Adds screenshots and release notes to the store listing</li>
          <li>Ships a higher-resolution application icon</li>
          <li>Drops a sandbox permission the application does not use</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Distribution and packaging release.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Published to the Ubuntu PPA, with classic Snap and Flatpak packaging</li>
          <li>Install-verification in CI asserts each package actually ships its rule pack</li>
          <li>Browser-driven interface tests for the desktop app</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic fixes and remote scanning.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Reversible fixes for file permissions and SSH server configuration,
              previewed before they are applied</li>
          <li>Scan a remote machine over SSH, with an isolated per-host history</li>
          <li>Secret-detection accuracy fixes, removing false positives from
              placeholders and test fixtures</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
